Guide to the David Benjamin Mixner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1930-2011; Accession 2012-M-039
  - Invitation to a holiday reception held at the White House, 2011 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, Circa 1940-1959, 2012; Accession 2012-M-048
  This accession comprises correspondence in the form of email printouts and a family genealogy.
  - Correspondence, 2012 January-February (Box 1, Folder 1-22)
  - Manuscript of the Mixner family genealogy, "Mid 1940s to Mid 1950s," by Patricia Mixner Annison, David's sister, Circa 1940-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 23-27)
- Additional Material, 2012; Accession 2012-M-052
  - Correspondence, 2012 February-March (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Correspondence, 2012 March-April (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Manuscript of the Mixner family genealogy, by Patricia Mixner Annison, David's sister, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    The manuscript documents the history of the Mixner family from 1960 to 1966.
- Additional Material, 2012; Accession 2013-M-002
  - Correspondence, 2012 April-May (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
  - Correspondence, 2012 May (Box 2, Folder 1-12)
  - Genealogy addenda/errata, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Get well cards, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, Circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Additional Material, 1964-2012; Accession 2013-M-009
  - Travel journals
    - Mixner, David, "Tanzania and Kenya, a Wonder Safari and Cairo, Egypt, Following the Nile", 1981 January 6-February 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annison, Patricia Mixner, "An African Journal: A Dream Comes True", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Play: Bailey, Dennis and David Mixner, Jacob's Ladder, 2008 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Family letters compiled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Note card and fundraiser invitation, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - E-mail printouts
      - 2012 June (Box 1, Folder 6-12)
      - 2012 June-July (Box 2, Folder 1-13)
      - 2012 July (Box 3, Folder 1-15)
      - 2012 August (Box 4, Folder 1-14)
- Additional Material, 2012; Accession 2013-M-044
  - Correspondence, 2012 September (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - Correspondence, 2012 September-October (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
- Additional Material, 1967-2013; Accession 2013-M-052
  - Correspondence, 2012 October (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence, 2012 November (Box 2, Folder 1-12)
  - Correspondence, 2012 November (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence, 2013 January (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
  - Compiled family correspondence, 1967-1968
    - 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, 2013; Accession 2013-M-057
  - Correspondence, 2013 January (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
  - Correspondence, 2013 February (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
  - Invitation to the 24th GLAAD media awards, 2013 March 16 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Additional Material, 2013; Accession 2013-M-070
  This accession consists of printed email correspondence from March through May 2013.
  - Correspondence, 2013 March (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
  - Correspondence, 2013 April (Box 2, Folder 1-13)
  - Correspondence, 2013 May (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
- Additional Material, 2013 June; Accession 2014-M-011
  This accession consists of printed email correspondence for June 2013.
  - Correspondence, 2013 June (Box 1, Folder 1-9, Box 2, Folder 1-6)
- Additional Material, 1967-2013; Accession 2014-M-014
  This accession consists of printed email correspondence, dated July-August 2013; additional family memoirs compiled by Mixner's sister, Patricia Mixner Annison; and Vietnam protest memorabilia, including newsletters of the Vietnam Moratorium Committee.
  - Correspondence, 2013 July-August (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
  - Family memoirs compiled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam protest memorabilia, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2-5)
- Additional Material, 1968-1984, 2013; Accession 2014-M-024
  This accession comprises correspondence in the form of email printouts, September-October 2013; political and protest materials, 1968-1970, 1983-1984, and 2013; and memoirs of 1972 by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2013.
  - Correspondence, 2013 September (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
  - Correspondence, 2013 October (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Material documenting political activities and protests
    - Eugene McCarthy flyers, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Vietnam War and antiballistic missile (ABM) protests and peace movement material, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Democratic Party structure and policy materials, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - McGovern Commission on Party Structure Youth Participation Subcommittee documents, 1970 July 28-29 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Municipal Elections Committee of Los Angeles (MECLA) calendar, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Emergency Fund materials, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Memoir documenting 1972 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, 1969-2013, undated; Accession 2014-M-033
  - Correspondence, 2013 November (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence, 2013 November-December (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Emergency Fund materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - March on Washington, 1969 November (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Memoir documenting 1973 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, 1968-2014; Accession 2014-M-043
  - Correspondence, 2013 December (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence, 2014 January (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence and position statements, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - New Democratic Coalition - California, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scientists and Engineers for McCarthy, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Additional Material, 1967-2014; Accession 2014-M-054
  This accession comprises correspondence in the form of email printouts, January-March 2014; political and protest materials, 1967-1974; and memoirs of 1974 by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2014.
  - Correspondence, 2014 January-March (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
  - Material documenting political activities and protests, 1967-1974
    - Chemical and biological weapons campaign, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - New Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietman, 1969 November (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Vietnam War protests, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Eugene McCarthy presidential campaign
      - General, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Illinois, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Iowa, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Minnesota, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - McCarthy Historical Project, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Maryland Task Force on Party Reform (Democratic), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - New Democratic Coalition (NDC)
      - Independent Democratic Coalition (IDC), Chicago, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Newsletters, meeting minutes, newsclippings, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Memoir documenting 1974 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, 1962-2014; Accession 2014-M-058
  - Correspondence, 2014 March (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence, 2014 April (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
  - Family Memoirs compiled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 1962-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fred R. Harris for President materials, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, 1976, 2014; Accession 2014-M-064
  This accession consists of printed email correspondence for April-May 2014 and memoir documenting 1976 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison.
  - Correspondence
    - 2014 April-May (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
    - 2014 May (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Memoir documenting 1976 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, 1977, 2014 May-June; Accession 2014-M-067
  - Correspondence
    - 2014 May (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - 2014 June (Box 2, Folder 1-10)
  - Family memoirs compiled by David Benjamin Mixner's sister, Patricia Mixner Annison., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, 1978-2014; Accession 2015-M-004
  - Correspondence
    - 2014 June (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    - 2014 July (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Family memoirs compiled by David B. Mixner's sister, Patricia Mixner Annison., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, 1979-2014; Accession 2015-M-015
  - Family memoirs, compiled by David B. Mixner's sister, Patricia Mixner Annison., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Photocopy of Jack Jones's book manuscript, "Chizi's Tale:The True Story of an Orphaned Black Rhino.", 2014 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence
    - 2014 August (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
    - 2014 September (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
- Additional Material, 1980-2014; Accession 2015-M-017
  - Correspondence
    - 2014 October (Box 1, Folder 1-12)
    - 2014 October (Box 2, Folder 1-10)
  - Family memoirs, compiled by David B. Mixner's sister, Patricia Mixner Annison., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, 1980-2014; Accession 2015-M-028
  - Correspondence
    - 2014 November-December (Box 1, Folder 1-12)
    - E-mail messages concerning "Fire in the Soul", 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Program and email messages concerning "Oh Hell No", 2014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Timed script for "Studio On Hudson", 2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Script of "The Unacceptable (The David Mixner Story)" by P. David Ebersole and Todd Hughes, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Edited versions of family memoirs, compiled by David B. Mixner's sister, Patricia Mixner Annison., 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - E-mail messages concerning the DCI Group, AZ, LLC, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, 1981-2015; Accession 2015-M-036
  - Correspondence
    - 2014 December (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - 2015 January (Box 1, Folder 4-13)
    - 2015 February (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Family memoirs, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, 1972-2015; Accession 2015-M-057; 1.92; (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - E-mail print-outs
      - 2014 November-2015 March (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
        Bulk of correspondence is February-March 2015.
      - 2015 April (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Paula Herzmark, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Family memoirs documenting 1982-1983 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Jacob's Ladder
    - Story line and publicity material, 2005, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Poster, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Additional Material, 2015; Accession 2015-M-070
  - Correspondence, 2015 May (Box 2, Folder 1-11)
  - Washington College commencement program (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Additional material, 1950s-2015; Accession 2015-M-080
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2015 May-June (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
  - Family memoirs documenting 1984 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Loose Threads," additions to family memoirs documenting 1959-1983 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Prints of digital copies of photographs, 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- Additional material, 2015; Accession 2016-M-009; .75; (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2015 June-August (Box 1, Folder 1-15, Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Family memoirs documenting 1985 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Additional material, 2015; Accession 2016-M-027
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2015 September-October (Box 1, Folder 1-16, Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Family memoir documenting 1986 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Additional material, 2011-2015; Accession 2016-M-043; .63; 2 boxes
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2015 November-December (Box 1, Folder 1-18)
  - At-A-Glance calendars, 2011-2013, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Additional material, Circa 2014-circa 2016; Accession 2016-M-0045 (Box 1)
  This accession consists two hard drives containing an interview with David Mixner. Topics in the interview include his childhood, politics in the 1960s, his coming out as a gay man, the AIDS epidemic, and equality legislation.
  The papers are closed until January 1, 2031, unless researchers receive permission in writing to access them from the donor, the person holding power of attorney for the donor, or the executor of the estate of the donor.
  - David Mixner Video Archive Master #2, 2016-M-0045-0001; 1 (Box 1)
  - David Mixner Video Archive Master, 2016-M-0045-0002; 1 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 2005-2016; Accession 2016-M-051
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2015 November-2016 March (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - At-A-Glance calendars, 2005, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
  - Family memoirs documenting 1987-1989 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2015-2016 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Audio-visual material
    - From the Front Porch: An Evening with David Mixner, recorded live at Dixon Place, 2011 July 18; 1 (Box 3)
    - 2013 Emery Awards: David Mixner Lifetime achievement Award, 1 (Box 4)
- Additional material, 2016-02; Accession 2016-M-0057
  Additional interview with David Benjamin Mixner by Jason Bellini in February 2016. Interview covers topics not included in previous longer interview by Bellini that was accessioned as 2016-M-0046.
  - Interview of David Benjamin Mixner by Jason Bellini, 2016-02; 2016-M-0057-0001; 1 (Reel 1)
- Additional material, 2016; Accession 2016-M-077
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2016 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
  - Family memoirs documenting 1990-1991 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Additional material, 2016; Accession 2017-M-007
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2016 May-July (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2016 July (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Family memoirs documenting 1992-1993 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
- Additional material, 2016; Accession 2017-M-034
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2016 August (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2016 September (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2016 October (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence (e-mail), 2016 November-December (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Family memoirs documenting 1994-1996 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
- Additional material, 2017; Accession 2017-M-054
  - Correspondence (email), 2017 January-March (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
  - Correspondence (email), 2017 March-April (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Hetrick-Martin Institute report and brochure, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Additional material, 1943-2017; Accession 2017-M-061
  Includes printed email correspondence, 2017 May-June, and family papers and correspondence pertaining to Robert M. Grove, Sr. (David Benjamin Mixner's grandfather); Robert M. Grove, Jr. and Donald Grove (David Benjamin Mixner's uncles); Robert M. Grove III (David Benjamin Mixner's cousin); Benjamin S. Mixner (David Benjamin Mixner's father); and Melvin B. Mixner II (David Benjamin Mixner's brother).
  - Correspondence (email), 2017 May-June (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
  - R. M. Grove, Sr. correspondence, 1945-1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - R. M. Grove, Jr. correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - R. M. Grove, Jr. correspondence, 1945-1945 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - R. M. Grove, Jr. family news clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - R. M. Grove, Jr. letters and memorabilia, 1940-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - R. M. Grove, Jr. family papers, 1944-1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - R. M. Grove, III death, 1955-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Donald Grove correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - Melvin B. Mixner correspondence, 1953-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Melvin B. Mixner and Donna Friedrick clippings, 1956-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - World War II mementos, 1943-1944, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Computer and email printouts, 1997-1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Program for 1969, 2017-2017 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Additional material, 2004-2017; Accession 2018-M-0013
  Printed email messages primarily between June and August 2017, with some from 2013; desk calendars, 2014, 2016, and 2017; family memoirs documenting 1969 and 1998 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison; and two CDs and a DVD of event recordings, 2004 and 2011.
  - Correspondence, 1993, 2003, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (email), 2014-2016 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (email), 2017-06-2017-08 (Box 1, Folder 3-14)
  - Correspondence (email), 2017-09- (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Desk calendars, 2014, 2016-2017 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - 1969 family memoirs, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1998 family memoirs, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for 1969, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Event recordings, 2004, 2011; 2; 1 (Box 3)
    The computer files are unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu. The request should outline the scope and purpose of the research project, why the researcher believes the material is relevant to their project, and contact information. If possible the request should also include a list of specific material of interest including collection, box, and folder numbers (or folder descriptions if folders are not numbered). The review may take several weeks.
    - From the Front Porch: An Evening with David Mixner Recorded live at Dixon Place July 18, 2011, 2018-M-0013-0001; 1 (Box 3)
    - From the Front Porch: An Evening with David Mixner Recorded live at Dixon Place July 18, 2011, 2018-M-0013-0002; 1 (Box 3)
    - Gay & Lesbian Victory Fund and Leadership Institute Breakthrough 2004 Oates-Shrum Award honoring Senator Edward M. Kennedy September 22, 2004, 2018-M-0013-0003; 1 (Box 3)
- Additional material, 2006-2017; Accession 2018-M-0029
  Printed email messages primarily between August and December 2017; magazines and publications; family memoirs documenting 1999 assembled by Patricia Mixner Annison; and two hard drives and a flash drive possibly documenting Mixner's video archive.
  - Correspondence (email), 2017-08 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (email), 2017-09 (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Correspondence (email), 2017-10 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - Correspondence (email), 2017-11 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Correspondence (email), 2017-12 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Magazines, email correspondence, and articles, 2006-2011 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1999 family memoirs, Circa 2006-2017 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Computer files (Box 3)
    - David Mixner Video Archive Backup, 2018-m-0029-0001; 1 (Box 3)
    - David Mixner Video Archive Backup #2, 2018-m-0029-0002; 1 (Box 3)
    - Additional footage, 2018-m-0029-0003; 1 (Box 3)
- Additional material, 2018-; Accession 2018-M-0046
  Printed email messages primarily between January and March 2018. Some folders include paper cards mailed to Mixner and Mixner's printed to do lists.
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-01- (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-02- (Box 1, Folder 4-8)
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-03- (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-03- (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Additional material, 2018-; Accession 2019-M-0005
  Printed email messages primarily between April and July 2018. Some folders include paper cards mailed to Mixner and Mixner's printed to do lists.
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-04- (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-05- (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-06- (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-06- (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence (email), 2018-07- (Box 2, Folder 6-8)